proximus.be 2014-03-31

# Privacy policy

Privacy policy
Dear Customer
Belgacom understands that privacy is very important for you, and we do our best to respect it.
That is why your personal data is only used by the Belgacom group; it is never communicated, without your prior
consent, to third parties for commercial purposes.
At the same time Belgacom commits to always keeping you informed about its special offers and promotions that
are likely to interest you. However, if you do not wish to receive commercial messages from us, you can easily indicate
this anytime you want via one of the many communication channels (email, 0800 number, web), and we will make sure
that your choice is respected.
The sections below detail how Belgacom handles your personal data when you use our services, such as fixed and
mobile telephony, the Internet, Belgacom TV and our other audiovisual services, and when you visit our websites
belgacom.be, belgacom.com, skynet.be and m.skynet.be.
Collection and use of personal data
Secrecy of telecommunications
Securing your personal data
Disclosure of personal data to third parties
Privacy policy relating to our websites
Privacy policy relating to Belgacom TV and other audiovisual services of Belgacom such as TV Everywhere
Your wish for privacy
The Do Not Call Me List
Your right of inspection and correction
Changes to our privacy policy
Page 1 of 5

Collection and use of personal data
If you want to use our services, you may be asked for some personal data, such as your first and last name, address,
login, e-mail address, telephone number, mobile number, date of birth, language, and a copy of your identity card. We
may also ask for other data which we need to deliver the service, such as specific preferences and requirements related
to the service concerned.
Personal data can be collected through various channels: e.g. orally in the Belgacom points-of-sale, by telephone via
the customer service, in writing via order forms or via electronic forms on the websites or via SMS. We can collect your
personal data when you place an order, take part in a survey or competition, call the customer service, subscribe to a
newsletter, or ask us for information. Your bill and payment data is also stored.
In addition, we collect data on your use of our services and websites and on the communication traffic that flows
through our network. Communication traffic can include the called fixed-line and mobile numbers, and the date, time
and duration of a call or Internet connection. We can also use socio-demographic data that we buy from specialized
agencies.
The personal data you enter via these different channels is stored in files held by Belgacom SA under public law (27 Bd.
du Roi Albert II, B-1030 Brussels). This data is used to deliver the required service or information, to establish and bill
the connection with the electronic communication networks of other operators, for customer administration, to draw up
and distribute telephone guides and offer directory assistance, to market the telephone numbers and addresses
mentioned in the telephone guides, for dispute management, to combat fraud and infringements committed against
Belgacom, its employees, customers or suppliers, to improve the quality of the services, for the planning and
organization of the telecommunications infrastructure, for market research and customer profiling, and to provide
information about our products, services and offers. All the data we collect can be combined to better adapt our offers
to your personal needs.
If you do not wish to receive any information about our products and services, or if you do have a specific preference
regarding the communication channels we use to inform you, or if you do not want us to adapt our offer to your usage
pattern, you can find out how to prevent this in the "Your wish for privacy" section.
The personal data are stored for up to 10 years after a person has ceased to be a Belgacom customer. Shorter storage
times apply to certain types of data, such as traffic data related to communications and connections, which are only
kept for 12 months.
According to the law, all processing of consumer data has been notified to the Commission for the Protection of Privacy.
Belgacom’s identification number for these notifications is HM 133424. Notification has been filed for several purposes,
such as customer management, direct marketing, market research, customer profiling, litigation management, fraud
combating, telephone directories, trade in personal data and camera surveillance.
Secrecy of telecommunications
The content of the communication traffic that flows through our network as fixed and mobile telephone calls, e-mails,
SMS messages and your surfing behavior on the Internet on other websites than those belonging to Belgacom, is
protected by the laws concerning the secrecy of telecommunications. This means that Belgacom and its employees may
not have any knowledge of such content. Belgacom has taken the necessary security measures and given strict
instructions to its employees to respect the secrecy of telecommunications.
The telephone calls you make to our customer service may be recorded to serve as evidence in case of a dispute about
a commercial transaction. Said telephone calls can also be recorded and listened to by a quality control monitor.
Securing your personal data
We have taken technical and organizational measures to protect the databases in which your data is kept against
unauthorized access, unauthorized use, theft or loss. Our security measures are regularly evaluated and adapted so
that we can continue to provide a high level of protection.
Disclosure of personal data to third parties
Some of our databases may be accessible to third parties working for us or assisting us with the performance of our
tasks, e.g. our partners or call centres who sell Belgacom services in our name and on our behalf. Such third parties
only have access to this data on a need-to-know basis, to enable them to perform their task on our behalf.
Your personal data and the data on the Belgacom products and services you use, can be shared with the subsidiaries of
the Belgacom Group to keep you informed about the products and services of the entire Belgacom Group. In case of
non-payment, we can inform our subsidiaries about your payment habits in order to protect the interests of the
Belgacom Group.
If you agreed to have your fixed-line and/or mobile number listed in the telephone guide and/or in the directory
assistance file, we will pass this data on to Directory Information Services, a Belgacom department which deals with the
telephone guides and the 1405 directory assistance service. You can ask for changes to your listing by calling the toll-
free number 0800 98 022 (NL) or 0800 98 033 (FR) or via an e-mail to gids@1207.be or annuaire@1307.be.
If you submit a complaint via the telecommunications ombudsman's service, for the handling of your complaint, we
may have to pass on your data to the ombudsman's service.
For the rest, we do not give the collected data to third parties, unless we explicitly state that this is required for a
specific action, or unless we are required by law to provide said data, e.g. at the request of the competent legal
authorities in the framework of a judicial enquiry.
Page 2 of 5

Privacy policy relating to our websites
You can visit our websites (belgacom.be, belgacom.com, skynet.be and m.skynet.be) without having to enter any
personal data. Access to certain parts or functions of our websites may be limited to visitors with an account on
skynet.be or an e-Services account from Belgacom and/or Proximus, after the correct password and login have been
entered.
Connection data
We also register information about the connection you make to our websites and the software and devices you use to
accomplish this. This information includes your IP address, the time of your visit to the website, the type of browser
and the type of device you use and the pages you visit. This data is used to create statistics and improve the quality of
our website and service through the analyses of your surfing behavior on our website.
If you visit a Belgacom website, we can use your surfing behavior on our websites and other data we have collected to
offer you a more personalized set of services and products which are tailored to your specific needs.
If you are a Belgacom customer for your access to the Internet, Belgacom can identify your IP address and link it to
your customer data so that based on all the collected data we can offer you a more personalized set of services that
might interest you. If you do not want this, you can find out how to prevent it in the "Your wish for privacy" section.
Comments and content that you enter on www.skynet.be
If the comments or content you enter in the Skynet News section on Skynet fora or in a Skynet blog give rise to
complaints, or if your comments or content do not correspond with the terms and conditions of use and the "Code on
Illegal Content" which you will find on www.skynet.be, this can be registered in our databases so that the appropriate
measures can be taken, e.g. remove the content or comment, or delete your profile. Your data can also be transferred
to the judicial authorities at their request in the framework of our obligation to inform the public prosecutor of any
illegal content. If you are not a Belgacom customer for your access to the Internet, the judicial authorities may obtain
your identity via your Internet Service Provider using your IP address. You can find more information about this in the
"terms and conditions of use" and the "Code on Illegal Content" on www.skynet.be.
Belgacom’s cookie policy
What are cookies?
A cookie is a text file that is installed in the browser of your computer or mobile device by a website's server when you
consult a website. The cookie contains a unique code which makes it possible for your browser to be recognized when
you visit the website ("session" cookies) or during subsequent, repeated visits ("permanent" cookies). Cookies can be
installed by the server of the website you visit or by partners of that website. A website's server can only read the
cookies it has installed itself, and has no access to other information found in your computer or mobile device. Cookies
are stored in the folder of your browser on your computer or mobile device. A cookie usually consists of the name of
the server that placed the cookie, an expiry date, and a unique number code.
Cookies generally make the interaction between the visitor and the website faster and easier, and help the visitor
navigate between the different parts of a website. Cookies can also be used to make the content or advertisement on a
website more relevant for the visitor, and can be adapted to his personal taste and needs.
Cookies used on Belgacom's websites
Different kinds of cookies are used on Belgacom's websites.
1/ Necessary cookies
These cookies are indispensable for visiting our websites and using certain parts of the websites. For instance, they
allow you to navigate between the different parts of the website, fill in forms, place orders, and maintain the contents
of your shopping cart. Even when you log in with your personal account, e.g. on the web portal of Skynet or the
Belgacom e-Services, these cookies are needed to check your identity in a secure way before you are granted access to
your personal data. If you refuse these cookies, certain parts of the website will not work, or will not work optimally.
2/ Functional cookies
Functional cookies are cookies that make it easier for our websites to work, make them more pleasant for visitors, and
ensure that you have a more personalized browsing experience. For example, these cookies can remember your
language choice and customer segment, or whether you were already asked to participate in a survey so that you are
not asked again the next time you visit the website.
3/ Performance cookies
We use performance cookies to obtain information about visitors' use of our websites, in order to improve the content
of our websites, adapt them to the wishes of visitors, and make them more user-friendly. For instance, there is a cookie
that counts the number of unique visitors, and a cookie that keeps track of the most popular pages.
4/ Advertisement cookies
Belgacom Skynet Advertising is a division of Belgacom which operates an online advertisement network.
When you visit our Skynet.be and JustForYou.be websites, Belgacom Skynet Advertising collects socio-demographic
details and profile data and stores them anonymously in an advertisement cookie.
Page 3 of 5

Via cookies (a.o. from Google or Criteo) and web beacons Belgacom Skynet Advertising also collects information on
your surfing behavior on various other websites which form part of its advertisement network. A web beacon is a small,
transparent image that stores information about your browsing behavior on one or more websites. Other advertisement
cookies are installed by the advertisers when their advertisement is published on the website.
Advertisement cookies do not contain personal data.
The information collected via these advertisement cookies and web beacons is used to measure the efficiency of the
advertising and to tailor the advertisements to your potential interests, not only on our websites but also on other
websites which form part of the advertisement network or to which Belgacom Skynet Advertising provides advertising
services.Managing cookies
You can refuse the installation of cookies via your browser settings. You can also remove cookies already installed on
your computer or mobile device at any time.
On the following website, you will find the procedure for refusing and removing cookies on the most popular browsers:
http://support.en.belgacom.be/app/answers/detail/a_id/15510
If you want to refuse the advertisement cookies (a.o. from Google or Criteo), you can do so via the website
http://www.youronlinechoices.com/be-fr/
Hyperlinks
Our websites may contain hyperlinks to websites that are not managed by Belgacom. Such hyperlinks are provided
purely for information purposes. When consulting such websites, we recommend that you carefully read their privacy
policy.
Tracking of commercial e-mails from Belgacom
Belgacom may send you e-mails in order to keep you informed about its existing and new products, services and
promotions, unless you have exercised your right to object. Belgacom uses tools to measure and follow up the impact
of these e-mails: has the e-mail been opened or not, has the hyperlink been clicked on or not, etc. These tools are used
to increase the efficiency of e-mail campaigns and to better adapt Belgacom’s offers to your personal needs.
Privacy policy relating to Belgacom TV and other audiovisual services of Belgacom such as TV Everywhere
The data that you provide to Belgacom via different channels and the data that Belgacom collects on your use of the
Belgacom TV services or other audiovisual Belgacom services, are incorporated into Belgacom's databases (27 Bd. du
Roi Albert II, 1030 Brussels).
The Belgacom TV decoder is equipped with software which registers and stores the operations carried out.
This data can be processed to:
      •    allow the successful implementation of the contract;
      •    ensure the correct delivery of the Belgacom TV services and other audiovisual Belgacom services;
      •    enable us to provide you with personalized recommendations regarding the Belgacom TV services;
      •    allow customer management;
      •    conduct market surveys and draw up user profiles;
      •    detect fraud, e.g. breaches of intellectual property rights;
      •    conduct information or promotional campaigns related to Belgacom Group products and services, including by
           post and/or e-mail. This information can be personalized according to your use of the products and services
           offered by Belgacom.
If you do not wish to be contacted, please read the instructions in the "Your wish for privacy" section on how to inform
us about this.
If you prefer non-personalized rather than personalized recommendations regarding the Belgacom TV services, please
inform us of your choice via the selection menu on your TV screen.
The data on your use of the Belgacom TV services is stored for 12 months.
The data that is collected can be disclosed to partners assisting Belgacom in the delivery of the Belgacom TV services or
in the event that such disclosure is necessary for the delivery of the service, or if you have authorized such disclosure.
Your wish for privacy
If you do not wish to receive information about Belgacom products and services, or if you object to your data being
shared with Belgacom Group subsidiaries for direct marketing purposes, please read the instructions here on how to
inform us of your wishes. Please take into account that adapting our systems to the new preferences can take a few
weeks.
      •    You are a Belgacom customer:
           If you have access to the e-Services on the Belgacom website, you can also inform us of your wishes with
           respect to receiving information via: My administration Be the first to know  a pop-up will appear in
           which you can select your preference per communication channel.
           If you do not wish to receive personalized recommendations from Belgacom based on your calling habits or
           surfing behavior on our websites after the identification of your IP address, in the list of communication
           channels you must select "No" for all the channels, and we will not use this data, neither send you
           commercial messages.
           You can call the toll-free number 0800 99 487 to inform us of your wish for privacy with respect to the
           sending of information about Belgacom products and services.
Page 4 of 5

          You can call the toll-free number 0800 99 981 if you object to your data being shared with Belgacom Group
          subsidiaries for direct marketing purposes.
          If you do not want your data which is published in the telephone guide to be commercialized, you can inform
          us by calling the toll-free number 0800 98 022 (NL) or 0800 98 033 (FR) or via an e-mail to gids@1207.be or
          annuaire@1307.be.
          You can call the toll-free number 6030 from your Proximus mobile phone and inform us of your wish for
          privacy.
      •   You are not a Belgacom customer:
          You can call one of the following numbers to inform us of your wish for privacy:
          0800 55 800 for private persons, professionals and SMEs;
          0800 55 200 for medium-sized and large companies and public institutions.
The Do-Not Call Me List
If you do not wish to receive commercial calls from any company or organization, you may register on the Do-Not Call
Me List via the website www.bel-me-niet-meer.be/ or www.ne-m-appelez-plus.be or you may send a letter to the
Belgian Direct Marketing Association at the address Noordkustlaan 1, 1702 Groot-Bijgaarden.
All companies and organizations that make offers by telephone or GSM are obliged by law to comply with this list.
Each company or organization is responsible for compliance with the Do-Not Call Me List. They are bound to withdraw
your telephone number and your name from their files and they are no longer allowed to call you in order to propose
their products or services? or their special promotions. Belgacom has no powers to supervise and control this.
For any complaints regarding unsolicited commercial calls, you can contact the Federal public service FPS Economy,
SMEs, Self-Employed and Energy, Contact Center, Rue du Progrès 50, 1210 Bruxelles or call to the toll-free number
0800 120 33.
Your right of inspection and correction
You have the right to consult and, if necessary, rectify your personal data. To do so, send a request (dated and signed)
with a copy of your identity card to Belgacom Group Legal Services (27 Bd. du Roi Albert II, 1030 Brussels).
Changes to our privacy policy
Our privacy policy may be extended or adapted in the future (for example, to accommodate new developments). For
this reason, we recommend that you consult this privacy policy regularly.
Page 5 of 5
